Rick Clark

Rookie MERN Stack Developer (with a robust health science background)

Salt Lake City, UT 84103 rickdclark48@gmail.com 2067958619

I am a laboratory technologist with two years experience in an immunology lab. Prior to that I attended two years of medical school, at the University of Utah, but decided that wasn't the right fit. I will graduate from the University of Utah Trilogy coding bootcamp in February 2019. At this time, I am focusing on a career in web development.

From creating a relationship with patients, to interpreting lab results, to mastering fundamentals of human science; I have developed a passion for understanding people. As a developer, I make applications that are concise, user-friendly, and technically sound. My health science background makes me uniquely valuable to development efforts by healthcare companies. Moreover, my dedication, enthusiasm, and growing skill-set will be an asset to any type of web development work.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Laboratory Technologist I

ARUP Laboratories, Cellular and Innate Immunology Division - Salt Lake City, UT April 2016 to July 2018

Perform assays that require expertise in cell culture, cell isolation, operation of a flow cytometer, and operation of a Luminex instrument.

Medical Student

Primary Care Clerkship - Orem, UT January 2013 to January 2015

University of Utah Health Care Clinic in Orem, Utah and in Murray, Utah

Conduct patient history taking, physical exams, and special procedures under the instruction of Dr. Miguel Villalobos and Dr. Keith Vancuran

Research Assistant NIH Grant

University of Utah Department of Trauma Surgery - Salt Lake City, UT May 2013 to August 2013

Conduct literature review exploring the relationship between blood thinners, traumatic brain injuries, and mortality in elderly individuals with atrial fibrillation. Work under the supervision of the P.I. Dr. Ram Nirula

Research Assistant Electrophysiology

Brigham Young University College of Life Sciences - Provo, UT January 2010 to June 2012

Conduct electrophysiology experiments on rat and mice hippocampal cells. Record, analyze, and present data for two research papers. Commitment of six hours per week during this period.

HIV Counselor

STD Testing - Salt Lake City, UT September 2010 to January 2012

Carry out client testing for HIV and other STDs, educate clients on risk reduction, participate in public outreach

Intern Maternal and Reproductive Health Clinic

USAID Reproductive Clinic June 2010 to August 2010

Cochabamba, Bolivia

Offer phlebotomy services, aid in physician clinical visits and surgeries, obtain vitals and history from patients

Education

Full Stack Web Developer in Trilogy Coding Bootcamp

University of Utah Professional Education - Salt Lake City, UT August 2018 to February 2019

Withdrawal - No Degree Awarded

University of Utah School of Medicine - Salt Lake City, UT August 2012 to August 2015

B.S. in Physiology and Developmental Biology

Brigham Young University - Provo, UT August 2006 to April 2012

Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, React (Less than 1 year)

Links

https://rclark4958.github.io/updated-portfolio/